[
  {
    "number": 1,
    "question": "Who said 'Man is of all forms of luggage the most difficult to transport'?",
    "options": ["Ricardo", "Adam Smith", "Alfred Marshal", "J.M. Keynes"],
    "answer": "Alfred Marshal"
  },
  {
    "number": 2,
    "question": "Which state of India is known as 'Land of Dawn'?",
    "options": ["Sikkim", "Orissa", "Tripura", "Arunachalpradesh"],
    "answer": "Arunachalpradesh"
  },
  {
    "number": 3,
    "question": "The biggest tributary of the river Ganga:",
    "options": ["Yamuna", "Krishna", "Kaveri", "Godavari"],
    "answer": "Yamuna"
  },
  {
    "number": 4,
    "question": "Gandhiji's first satyagraha in India is at:",
    "options": ["Kheda", "Sabarmati", "Champaran", "Chauri chaura"],
    "answer": "Champaran"
  },
  {
    "number": 5,
    "question": "Who set up 'Servants of India Society'?",
    "options": ["Tilak", "Lala Lajpatrai", "Bipin Chandrapal", "Gopalakrishna Gokhale"],
    "answer": "Gopalakrishna Gokhale"
  },
  {
    "number": 6,
    "question": "Which article of the Indian constitution deals with Election commission?",
    "options": ["Article 352", "Article 324", "Article 370", "Article 24"],
    "answer": "Article 324"
  },
  {
    "number": 7,
    "question": "The instrument used to measure the specific gravity of liquids:",
    "options": ["Hydrometer", "Hydrophone", "Hygrometer", "Micrometer"],
    "answer": "Hydrometer"
  },
  {
    "number": 8,
    "question": "Oil and Natural Gas Commission (ONGC) set up in:",
    "options": ["1950", "1951", "1956", "1954"],
    "answer": "1956"
  },
  {
    "number": 9,
    "question": "Who has been selected for the J.C. Daniel award for 2014 in recognition of his contribution to the Malayalam film industry?",
    "options": ["I.V. Sasi", "Kamal", "Adoor Gopalakrishnan", "Jayaraj"],
    "answer": "Kamal"
  },
  {
    "number": 10,
    "question": "The First President of Indian National Congress:",
    "options": ["S.N. Bannerji", "A.O. Hume", "Lord Dufferin", "W.C. Bannerji"],
    "answer": "W.C. Bannerji"
  },
  {
    "number": 11,
    "question": "Kuriakose Elias Chavara died in:",
    "options": ["1871", "1805", "1850", "1860"],
    "answer": "1871"
  },
  {
    "number": 12,
    "question": "Who founded Sadhujanaparipalana Sangham?",
    "options": ["Pandit Karuppan", "Dr. Palpu", "Ayyankali", "V.T. Bhattathiripad"],
    "answer": "Ayyankali"
  },
  {
    "number": 13,
    "question": "The book 'Anandadarshanam' is written by:",
    "options": ["Sahodaran Ayyappan", "Brahmananda Sivayogi", "Vaikunda Swamikal", "Chattampi Swamikal"],
    "answer": "Brahmananda Sivayogi"
  },
  {
    "number": 14,
    "question": "Sree Narayanaguru was born at:",
    "options": ["Chempazhanthi", "Varkala", "Aluva", "Thiruvillamala"],
    "answer": "Chempazhanthi"
  },
  {
    "number": 15,
    "question": "Chattampi Swamikal attained Samadhi at:",
    "options": ["Kannanmoola", "Sivagiri", "Venganoor", "Panmana"],
    "answer": "Panmana"
  },
  {
    "number": 16,
    "question": "Headquarters of Prathyaksha Raksha Daiva Sabha (PRDS):",
    "options": ["Palakkad", "Iraviperoor", "Neyyattinkara", "Kainakari"],
    "answer": "Eraviperoor"
  },
  {
    "number": 17,
    "question": "'Adukkalayilninnu Arangathekku' is a:",
    "options": ["Novel", "Poetry", "Short story", "Drama"],
    "answer": "Drama"
  },
  {
    "number": 18,
    "question": "'Jathikummi' written by:",
    "options": ["Pandit Karuppan", "Thycaud Ayya", "Kumaranasan", "Agamananda Swamikal"],
    "answer": "Pandit Karuppan"
  },
  {
    "number": 19,
    "question": "Nair Service Society founded on:",
    "options": ["1st October 1914", "31st December 1914", "31st October 1914", "1st January 1914"],
    "answer": "31st October 1914"
  },
  {
    "number": 20,
    "question": "The 'Swadeshabhimani' owned by:",
    "options": ["Abdul Rahman", "Vakkom Abdul Khadar Moulavi", "K. Ramakrishna Pillai", "K.P. Kesavamenon"],
    "answer": "Vakkom Abdul Khadar Moulavi"
  },
  {
    "number": 21,
    "question": "In India the new flag code came into being in:",
    "options": ["1950 January 26", "1947 August 15", "1951 January 26", "2002 January 26"],
    "answer": "2002 January 26"
  },
  {
    "number": 22,
    "question": "Who won the Nobel Prize for Economics in 2015?",
    "options": ["Jean Tirole", "Angus Deaton", "Patrick Modiano", "Amartya Sen"],
    "answer": "Angus Deaton"
  },
  {
    "number": 23,
    "question": "Capital of Cuba:",
    "options": ["Havana", "Ottava", "Capetown", "Ankara"],
    "answer": "Havana"
  },
  {
    "number": 24,
    "question": "Who wrote the play 'Waiting for Godot'?",
    "options": ["Thomas Mann", "T.S. Eliot", "Samuel Becket", "Franz Kafka"],
    "answer": "Samuel Becket"
  },
  {
    "number": 25,
    "question": "The study and collection of paper currency and banknotes is:",
    "options": ["Notaphily", "Graphology", "Epigraphy", "Paleography"],
    "answer": "Notaphily"
  },
  {
    "number": 26,
    "question": "National Drinking Water Mission started in:",
    "options": ["1981", "1986", "1980", "1991"],
    "answer": "1986"
  },
  {
    "number": 27,
    "question": "The first climate change theatre in India was opened in:",
    "options": ["Agarthala", "Chandranagar", "Gandhinagar", "Kapurthala"],
    "answer": "Kapurthala"
  },
  {
    "number": 28,
    "question": "Director of the film 'Bicycle Thieves':",
    "options": ["Vittorio de sica", "Satyajit Ray", "Akira Kurosawa", "Alfred Hitchcock"],
    "answer": "Vittorio de sica"
  },
  {
    "number": 29,
    "question": "'Guernica' is the famous painting of:",
    "options": ["Vangogh", "Rodin", "Pablo Picasso", "Salvador Dali"],
    "answer": "Pablo Picasso"
  },
  {
    "number": 30,
    "question": "'The Test of My Life' is written by:",
    "options": ["Kapil Dev", "Yuvaraj Singh", "Sunil Gavaskar", "Sachin Tendulkar"],
    "answer": "Yuvaraj Singh"
  },
  {
    "number": 31,
    "question": "Which of the following has the fastest type of memory?",
    "options": ["Semiconductor Memories", "Magnetic Disks", "Magnetic Tapes", "Compact Disks"],
    "answer": "Semiconductor Memories"
  },
  {
    "number": 32,
    "question": "ROM has a:",
    "options": ["Decoder followed by encoder", "Multiplexer followed by decoder", "Demultiplexer followed by an encoder", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "None of the above"
  },
  {
    "number": 33,
    "question": "The smallest information that computer can understand:",
    "options": ["Unicode", "Bit", "ASCII", "Byte"],
    "answer": "Bit"
  },
  {
    "number": 34,
    "question": "_____ is a technique used for processing bank cheques.",
    "options": ["MICR", "OMR", "OCR", "DDR"],
    "answer": "MICR"
  },
  {
    "number": 35,
    "question": "1 Gigabyte means:",
    "options": ["2^10 bytes", "2^20 bytes", "2^30 bytes", "2^40 bytes"],
    "answer": "2^30 bytes"
  },
  {
    "number": 36,
    "question": "_____ memory is non volatile.",
    "options": ["Cache", "Primary", "Secondary", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Secondary"
  },
  {
    "number": 37,
    "question": "Which of the following device can store large amounts of data?",
    "options": ["Floppy Disk", "Hard Disk", "CDROM", "Zip Disk"],
    "answer": "Hard Disk"
  },
  {
    "number": 38,
    "question": "The list of coded instructions is called:",
    "options": ["Computer program", "Algorithm", "Flowchart", "Utility programs"],
    "answer": "Computer program"
  },
  {
    "number": 39,
    "question": "What is M-commerce?",
    "options": ["Manual Commerce", "Mobile Commerce", "Marketing Commerce", "Money Commerce"],
    "answer": "Mobile Commerce"
  },
  {
    "number": 40,
    "question": "In Ms-Excel which is shortcut key for getting 'Current Time':",
    "options": ["Ctrl + shift + t", "Ctrl + shift +;", "Ctrl+t", "Ctrl+;"],
    "answer": "Ctrl + shift +;"
  },
  {
    "number": 41,
    "question": "URL is the abbreviation of:",
    "options": ["Universal Resource Locator", "Universal Report Locator", "Uniform Resource Locator", "Uniform Report Label"],
    "answer": "Uniform Resource Locator"
  },
  {
    "number": 42,
    "question": "etc. is the abbreviation of:",
    "options": ["exetra", "et cetera", "extra", "ex-cetera"],
    "answer": "et cetera"
  },
  {
    "number": 43,
    "question": "SMS means:",
    "options": ["Small Message Sender", "Short Mobile Sender", "Short Mobile Service", "Short Message Service"],
    "answer": "Short Message Service"
  },
  {
    "number": 44,
    "question": "The size of an A4 paper is:",
    "options": ["8.5\" ×11\"", "8.5\" x 14\"", "8.27\" ×11.69\"", "8.27\"×11\""],
    "answer": "8.27\" ×11.69\""
  },
  {
    "number": 45,
    "question": "While drafting the address of a letter, after 'from' and 'to' which punctuation mark is to be written?",
    "options": ["comma", "full stop", "quotation", "no mark"],
    "answer": "colon"
  },
  {
    "number": 46,
    "question": "Which function key is used for refreshing?",
    "options": ["F4", "F7", "F5", "F8"],
    "answer": "F5"
  },
  {
    "number": 47,
    "question": "No. of dead keys are in a modified Malayalam Typewriter?",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "One", "Four"],
    "answer": "Three"
  },
  {
    "number": 48,
    "question": "What are the short cut keys for getting a double underline to a selected text in MS. Word document?",
    "options": ["Ctrl + shift + d", "Ctrl + shift + u", "Ctrl + shift +1", "Ctrl +shift + 2"],
    "answer": "Ctrl + shift + d"
  },
  {
    "number": 49,
    "question": "The Maximum number of lines can be set for a Drop Cap is:",
    "options": ["5", "8", "10", "13"],
    "answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "number": 50,
    "question": "In computing the term IP means:",
    "options": ["Insert Pin", "International Pin", "Internet Protocol", "Internet Pin"],
    "answer": "Internet Protocol"
  },
  {
    "number": 51,
    "question": "From where, the CPU in a computer retrieves data:",
    "options": ["Main Memory", "Secondary Memory", "Auxiliary memory", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Main Memory"
  },
  {
    "number": 52,
    "question": "Which are short cut keys for converting the selected text into upper case in MS. Word?",
    "options": ["Ctrl + shift + 1", "Ctrl + shift + u", "Ctrl + shift + a", "Ctrl + shift + c"],
    "answer": "Ctrl + shift + a"
  },
  {
    "number": 53,
    "question": "The Key 'N' is called 'Master Key' in a typewriting keyboard because:",
    "options": ["right hand index finger is using for typing", "it is fixed on the bottom of the key board", "it is the first letter installed in the keyboard", "none of these"],
    "answer": "right hand index finger is using for typing"
  },
  {
    "number": 54,
    "question": "The Designer of Malayalam Typewriter Keyboard is:",
    "options": ["T.K. Ramakrishnan", "R. Arulappan", "N.S. Pandala", "T.R. Krishnayyer"],
    "answer": "N.S. Pandala"
  },
  {
    "number": 55,
    "question": "The unsolicited bulk commercial E-mails are known as:",
    "options": ["hoaxes", "virus", "junk", "spam"],
    "answer": "spam"
  },
  {
    "number": 56,
    "question": "RTF is the abbreviation of:",
    "options": ["Real Text Format", "Readable Text Form", "Rich Text Format", "Real Text Function"],
    "answer": "Rich Text Format"
  },
  {
    "number": 57,
    "question": "Name the computerised system which helps managers of big organisation for decision making?",
    "options": ["Network", "MIS", "Assembler", "Interpreter"],
    "answer": "MIS"
  },
  {
    "number": 58,
    "question": "The software installed on computers for collecting the information about the users without their knowledge is:",
    "options": ["Virus", "Worms", "Spyware", "Spam"],
    "answer": "Spyware"
  },
  {
    "number": 59,
    "question": "What is the meaning of 'Wiki' in the word 'Wikipedia'?",
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Around the world", "Quick", "Medium"],
    "answer": "Quick"
  },
  {
    "number": 60,
    "question": "The protection systems involve some unique aspect of a person's body is:",
    "options": ["Authorization", "Biometric", "Authentication", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Biometric"
  },
  {
    "number": 61,
    "question": "In which year the Government of India passed the Information Technology Act?",
    "options": ["1999", "2000", "2001", "2002"],
    "answer": "2000"
  },
  {
    "number": 62,
    "question": "Which of the following can be used for identification and tracking of products, animal etc.?",
    "options": ["RAID", "RFID", "Router", "None of these"],
    "answer": "RFID"
  },
  {
    "number": 63,
    "question": "SIM is the abbreviation of:",
    "options": ["Subscriber Identification Module", "Subscriber Information Machine", "Subscriber Information Mobile", "System of Information Mobile"],
    "answer": "Subscriber Identification Module"
  },
  {
    "number": 64,
    "question": "In MS. Word, pressing 'Alt + Backspace' gives the result of:",
    "options": ["Delete", "Redo", "Exit", "Undo"],
    "answer": "Undo"
  },
  {
    "number": 65,
    "question": "Find the odd one:",
    "options": ["ROM", "RAM", "EPROM", "PROM"],
    "answer": "RAM"
  },
  {
    "number": 66,
    "question": "A Court Case Number is written as OP 1/2015. Here OP stands for:",
    "options": ["Open Petition", "Opposite Party", "Other Party", "Original Petition"],
    "answer": "Original Petition"
  },
  {
    "number": 67,
    "question": "One KB is equal to:",
    "options": ["1000 bytes", "1012 bytes", "1014 bytes", "1024 bytes"],
    "answer": "1024 bytes"
  },
  {
    "number": 68,
    "question": "The Computers which have Artificial Intelligence is:",
    "options": ["1st Generation", "2nd Generation", "3rd Generation", "4th Generation"],
    "answer": "4th Generation"
  },
  {
    "number": 69,
    "question": "How many bits are in a nibble?",
    "options": ["4", "8", "16", "32"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "number": 70,
    "question": "The most important feature of cloud computing is:",
    "options": ["on demand service", "software service", "platform service", "infrastructure service"],
    "answer": "on demand service"
  },
  {
    "number": 71,
    "question": "In an MS. Word document, 'Ctrl + Delete' keys can be used for:",
    "options": ["delete a letter", "delete a row", "delete a paragraph", "delete a word"],
    "answer": "delete a word"
  },
  {
    "number": 72,
    "question": "Which is function key using for spelling checking?",
    "options": ["F3", "F5", "F7", "F9"],
    "answer": "F7"
  },
  {
    "number": 73,
    "question": "Which of the following is used to read PDF files?",
    "options": ["MS Word", "MS Excel", "Power Point", "Acrobat Reader"],
    "answer": "Acrobat Reader"
  },
  {
    "number": 74,
    "question": "G.Os are issued by:",
    "options": ["Governor", "Secretary", "Chief Minister", "Home Minister"],
    "answer": "Secretary"
  },
  {
    "number": 75,
    "question": "F.O.B means:",
    "options": ["Free On Boat", "Free On Business", "Free On Board", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Free On Board"
  },
  {
    "number": 76,
    "question": "MIPS means:",
    "options": ["Multiple Information Processing System", "Multiple Information Per Second", "Millions Instructions Per Second", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Millions Instructions Per Second"
  },
  {
    "number": 77,
    "question": "Which is a 'presentation software'?",
    "options": ["MS Access", "Power Point", "MS Excel", "Word Processor"],
    "answer": "Power Point"
  },
  {
    "number": 78,
    "question": "The mistake made in the typing-process of printed material is known as:",
    "options": ["Scribal error", "Typographical Error", "Clerical error", "Spelling error"],
    "answer": "Typographical Error"
  },
  {
    "number": 79,
    "question": "In MS Word document, Alt + F8 is the short-cut key for?",
    "options": ["Review", "Mailing", "Reference", "Macros"],
    "answer": "Macros"
  },
  {
    "number": 80,
    "question": "To print in wide format, which orientation is suited:",
    "options": ["Vertical", "Horizontal", "Portrait", "Landscape"],
    "answer": "Landscape"
  },
  {
    "number": 81,
    "question": "How cute the baby looks!",
    "options": ["Interrogative sentence", "Exclamatory sentence", "Declarative sentence", "Imperative sentence"],
    "answer": "Exclamatory sentence"
  },
  {
    "number": 82,
    "question": "My best friend and severest critic ___ my mother.",
    "options": ["was", "were", "are", "is"],
    "answer": "is"
  },
  {
    "number": 83,
    "question": "This is the dog ___ I bought yesterday.",
    "options": ["who", "that", "which", "whose"],
    "answer": "which"
  },
  {
    "number": 84,
    "question": "Have you heard the ___ news.",
    "options": ["latest", "later", "latter", "late"],
    "answer": "latest"
  },
  {
    "number": 85,
    "question": "Come here:",
    "options": ["quick", "quicker", "quickly", "quickest"],
    "answer": "quickly"
  },
  {
    "number": 86,
    "question": "Everyone respects ___ honest man.",
    "options": ["a", "an", "the", "that"],
    "answer": "an"
  },
  {
    "number": 87,
    "question": "In our childhood days, we ___ to take long walks.",
    "options": ["used", "ought", "dare", "need"],
    "answer": "used"
  },
  {
    "number": 88,
    "question": "One should not be too strict, ___?",
    "options": ["shall one", "would one", "shouldn't one", "should one"],
    "answer": "shouldn't one"
  },
  {
    "number": 89,
    "question": "I ___ you are wrong.",
    "options": ["think", "thinks", "thought", "are thinking"],
    "answer": "think"
  },
  {
    "number": 90,
    "question": "Unless you change your habits, ___:",
    "options": ["you would suffer", "you should suffer", "you will suffer", "you shall suffer"],
    "answer": "you will suffer"
  },
  {
    "number": 91,
    "question": "God has been kind ___ me.",
    "options": ["of", "for", "with", "to"],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "number": 92,
    "question": "'Don't overeat', said the doctor to the patient:",
    "options": [
      "The doctor warned the patient did not overeat",
      "The doctor warned the patient not to overeat",
      "The doctor requested patient you don't overeat",
      "The doctor requested the patient not to overeat"
    ],
    "answer": "The doctor warned the patient not to overeat"
  },
  {
    "number": 93,
    "question": "The passive form of 'Don't disturb the patient' is:",
    "options": [
      "Let the patient is not be disturbed",
      "Let the patient are not be disturbed",
      "Let not the patient be disturb",
      "Let not the patient be disturbed"
    ],
    "answer": "Let not the patient be disturbed"
  },
  {
    "number": 94,
    "question": "Complete the sentence using the appropriate idiom: Be careful lest you ___",
    "options": ["get into hot water", "get the better of", "hold water", "wash one's hand of"],
    "answer": "get into hot water"
  },
  {
    "number": 95,
    "question": "Find out the correct spelling of:",
    "options": ["warobe", "wardrobe", "wadrobe", "wardobe"],
    "answer": "wardrobe"
  },
  {
    "number": 96,
    "question": "One word substitute for 'a room where the food supplies of a household are kept':",
    "options": ["scullery", "buttery", "larder", "pantry"],
    "answer": "larder"
  },
  {
    "number": 97,
    "question": "I am sure he will ___ from this crisis.",
    "options": ["pull down", "pull through", "pull off", "pull up"],
    "answer": "pull through"
  },
  {
    "number": 98,
    "question": "A synonym for the word 'overjoyed':",
    "options": ["felicity", "happy", "jubiliant", "novice"],
    "answer": "jubiliant"
  },
  {
    "number": 99,
    "question": "The antonym of the word 'obscure':",
    "options": ["famous", "familiar", "fair", "foul"],
    "answer": "famous"
  },
  {
    "number": 100,
    "question": "The feminine gender of 'gentleman':",
    "options": ["woman", "maid", "gentle woman", "lady"],
    "answer": "lady"
  }
]